<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-01T16:48:49-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Release 0.3.0</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/release/2020/02/19/0.3.0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Release 0.3.0" /><published>2020-02-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/release/2020/02/19/0.3.0</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/release/2020/02/19/0.3.0.html">&lt;p&gt;First release for iOS beta!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bugfixes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ads are properly cleared on the paid version in all screens&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;fixed issue with swiping away ToDos crashing app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">First release for iOS beta!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retrospective on Launching the Public Beta for auToDo</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/startup-school/personal/meta/2020/02/06/beta-launch-retrospective.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retrospective on Launching the Public Beta for auToDo" /><published>2020-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/startup-school/personal/meta/2020/02/06/beta-launch-retrospective</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/startup-school/personal/meta/2020/02/06/beta-launch-retrospective.html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday marked a very important milestone in auToDo’s journey. The app was made
available to the public for the first time! It was released only for Android and
as a beta release, so it isn’t quite a fully public app yet. This is still a big
step up from the 3 users the app had before yesterday (including me) though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first side-project that I have launched as a public product. Launching
a product and trying to recruit beta testers is very new to me. Overall I was happy
with how the launch turned out, but I definitely learned a lot through the process
that will help with future launches of auToDo features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prep-for-launch&quot;&gt;Prep for Launch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put together a set of material that, to me, seemed like a good bit of content
for promoting auToDo. I had not done nearly enough research on other products on
Product Hunt in particular though, as my post was lacking the fun gifs and other
animations that the other products had. I put together a &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/SeWKZL1nUQY&quot;&gt;YouTube video&lt;/a&gt;
promoting auToDo, but that was not able to make it into the post. Lesson learned
there – if you don’t get the YouTube link correct or forget it when posting, you
won’t be able to go back and edit it later. Overall I would say that I spent way
more time on the YouTube promo video than it was worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The positive feedback that I received the most on the app’s launch was that the
screenshots were clean looking and indicated a good UI. A lot of the additional
material surrounding a launch like the branding and background story are nice
to have, but it seemed like people ultimately cared most about the content of
the app. That was a great sign for me; I much prefer making a great product than
trying to market it with smoke and mirrors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;launch-day&quot;&gt;Launch Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launching on Product Hunt generated a lot of traffic to my app compared to other
sources. I promoted the post in group chats with my friends and colleagues and
in Slack channels for other startup founders, but the majority of my app’s
downloads were from individuals that I did not know. I’m tentatively thinking
that this will be a good thing for the development of my app because it will
be good to get feedback from people who do not know me personally and want to
try to avoid hurting my feelings with negative feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the majority of people that I knew did not personally sign up as beta
testers, they did help tremendously in giving my post visibility on Product Hunt.
I was able to hold the last spot on the front page of Product Hunt for the
duration of my launch day, and I couldn’t have done it without the upvotes before
the official launch and during launch day from my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-user-feedback&quot;&gt;Getting user feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For better or worse, I made sure that there were a lot of different channels for
giving feedback on auToDo’s beta. I’ve gotten a lot of very helpful feedback so
far, but keeping track of the Play Store feedback and emails and Slack messages
and in-person reviews and… has been a bit tough. Some channels have given me
more in-depth feedback than others but I am thankful for the variety of responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I believe that it will be necessary to proactively reach out to
auToDo’s users for feedback on updates. It is very convenient that Play Store
updates are seamless but this means that there will not be the noticeable event
like a launch that prompts feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;startupschool-update&quot;&gt;StartupSchool Update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the rush to get auToDo launched I have not written a post about weeks 2 and 3
of the Startup School program. I think this is fitting with the intent of the
program though, getting a product in front of users is the most important
priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got some very good support and feedback from the other companies in week 3’s
group session. The other founders were also software developers so we were able
to bond over that foundation. The other founders were congratulatory of my launch,
which I appreciated, and gave me feedback that I needed to take that momentum
and run with it to maintain relationships between the users and auToDo rather
than trying to get traction exclusively through one-time promos like a launch.
That was a perspective that I had not focused on enough, especially with launch
so near, so it was a much needed piece of advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jonathan&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Yesterday marked a very important milestone in auToDo’s journey. The app was made available to the public for the first time! It was released only for Android and as a beta release, so it isn’t quite a fully public app yet. This is still a big step up from the 3 users the app had before yesterday (including me) though!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Release 0.2.0</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/release/2020/02/03/0.2.0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Release 0.2.0" /><published>2020-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/release/2020/02/03/0.2.0</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/release/2020/02/03/0.2.0.html">&lt;p&gt;First release to the public beta!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Added ads on the home screen and the option to pay a one time fee of $2.99 to remove the ads permanently.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">First release to the public beta!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Release 0.1.9</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/release/2020/02/02/0.1.9.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Release 0.1.9" /><published>2020-02-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/release/2020/02/02/0.1.9</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/release/2020/02/02/0.1.9.html">&lt;p&gt;Variety of bugfixes for the signup process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bugfixes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restored the ability to reset account password&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restored the ability to reach new account setup screen after email validation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restored the ability to switch between login and signup screens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Variety of bugfixes for the signup process.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Release 0.1.8</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/release/2020/01/26/0.1.8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Release 0.1.8" /><published>2020-01-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/release/2020/01/26/0.1.8</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/release/2020/01/26/0.1.8.html">&lt;p&gt;Improved a variety of minor UX annoyances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bugfixes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Autocomplete fields won’t clear contents when selecting an item no&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move the date picker icon so it is reachable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Show completed ToDo items as completed, rather than “upcoming”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configuring multiple cars in the new user setup screen actually adds all cars&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removed ability to bypass email verification on signup screen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added back the dialog for email verification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improvements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeating tasks now show the car they are associated with&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The snackbar that displays when signing in stays until the process completes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users with &amp;lt; 4 cars can use a set of toggle buttons for selecting a car in the refueling add/edit screen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removed dead link to old repeat editor screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Improved a variety of minor UX annoyances.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">YC Startup School Week 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/startup-school/personal/2020/01/24/startup-school-week-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="YC Startup School Week 1" /><published>2020-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/startup-school/personal/2020/01/24/startup-school-week-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/startup-school/personal/2020/01/24/startup-school-week-1.html">&lt;p&gt;This week I started in on Y Combinator’s Startup School program with the intention of launching auToDo soon. I have the knowledge and experience to write the app for auToDo, but that is definitely not the case for the other aspects of turning it into a successful business. Startup School’s goal is to make it easier for people like myself to navigate the confusing time of starting and running a startup, and I fully intend to make the most of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Startup School is designed to encourage founders to set one or two metrics and do everything they can to improve them. Since auToDo is not yet launched, my one and only metric to track is the time left to launch. As a result, everything I have worked on this week for auToDo has been intended to speed up the timeline to making the app public. auToDo should be going public on the Google Play Store some time in the next couple days; I’ll add the release notes here per usual when the public version is out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A highlight of the week was the Startup School Group Session, where I got a chance to speak with other founders in the program. I got helpful feedback on my website and got to extend feedback to the other companies as well. The other founders were non-technical founders, meaning that they did not create their products directly but acted in a more traditional CEO role. Their knowledge and experience was a good complement to my strictly technical experience. One major takeaway from the conversation is that I ought to move up my timeline on establishing auToDo as a corporation. Earning significant revenue and adding additional co-founders is nearly impossible otherwise, and those are two things I’d like to see happen in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jonathan&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This week I started in on Y Combinator’s Startup School program with the intention of launching auToDo soon. I have the knowledge and experience to write the app for auToDo, but that is definitely not the case for the other aspects of turning it into a successful business. Startup School’s goal is to make it easier for people like myself to navigate the confusing time of starting and running a startup, and I fully intend to make the most of it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Release 0.1.7</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/release/2020/01/20/0.1.7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Release 0.1.7" /><published>2020-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/release/2020/01/20/0.1.7</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/release/2020/01/20/0.1.7.html">&lt;p&gt;Hotfix for bug found in user testing where a previously signed-in user could not access the home screen.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hotfix for bug found in user testing where a previously signed-in user could not access the home screen.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Release 0.1.6</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/release/2020/01/19/0.1.6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Release 0.1.6" /><published>2020-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/release/2020/01/19/0.1.6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/release/2020/01/19/0.1.6.html">&lt;p&gt;No visible changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Added the BILLING permission to the app to allow for the future addition of in-app permissions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">No visible changes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Release 0.1.5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/release/2020/01/18/0.1.5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Release 0.1.5" /><published>2020-01-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/release/2020/01/18/0.1.5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/release/2020/01/18/0.1.5.html">&lt;p&gt;Major overhaul of the app’s business logic, so the number of noticeable bugs should be much lower than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trial option on signup, uses local phone storage with no need to create an account.
Bugfixes:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bugfixes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Text overflowing on Todo Cards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Todo items are not created for repeating tasks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Couldn’t open the add/edit screens multiple times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Major overhaul of the app’s business logic, so the number of noticeable bugs should be much lower than before.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Release 0.1.4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/release/2019/12/01/0.1.4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Release 0.1.4" /><published>2019-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/release/2019/12/01/0.1.4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/release/2019/12/01/0.1.4.html">&lt;p&gt;Improvements targeted at improving the sign up and sign in UX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forgot Password button&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email Verification for new accounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keyboard’s “next” and “done” buttons implemented&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Missing and broken form validation fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Improvements targeted at improving the sign up and sign in UX.</summary></entry></feed>